<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 14:37:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.8.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Lookbook: Ecommerce Design Inspiration for 2016</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/lookbook-ecommerce-design-inspiration-2016/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/lookbook-ecommerce-design-inspiration-2016/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 14:29:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Juan Manuel Molina]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21206</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The most successful PrestaShop online stores all have something in common: well thought-out design and outstanding images for backgrounds and products. The 2016 PrestaShop Lookbook features a selection of 24 examples of carefully chosen user interfaces, intelligent and use of color, and best practices, all of which drive conversions. Find inspiration in the most elegant [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/lookbook-ecommerce-design-inspiration-2016/">Lookbook: Ecommerce Design Inspiration for 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>The most successful PrestaShop online stores all have something in common:</strong> well thought-out design and outstanding images for backgrounds and products.</p>
<p>The 2016 PrestaShop Lookbook features a selection of 24 examples of carefully chosen user interfaces, intelligent and use of color, and best practices, all of which drive conversions.<span id="more-21206"></span></p>
<p>Find inspiration in the most elegant PrestaShop online stores as you feast your eyes on our unique ecommerce art gallery!</p>
<div class="text-center"><a class="btn btn-sucess" style="background-color: #2f2f2f;border: 1px solid #191717;border-bottom: 3px solid #292727;margin: 20px 0 0;color: #fff" href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/lookbook" target="_blank"><i class="fa fa-download"></i>   Download the Lookbook</a></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/lookbook-ecommerce-design-inspiration-2016/">Lookbook: Ecommerce Design Inspiration for 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/lookbook-ecommerce-design-inspiration-2016/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The merchant&#8217;s guide to Super Bowl 50</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/merchants-guide-super-bowl-50/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/merchants-guide-super-bowl-50/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 13:30:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21183</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The Super Bowl is the crowning night of America’s favorite pastime. Each year, football fans tune in to see who will take home the coveted Vince Lombardi Trophy, and the rest of America hangs around for the legendary commercials. Whether you’re a die-hard fan or dread Sunday nights in winter, we’re sharing 5 marketing ideas [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/merchants-guide-super-bowl-50/">The merchant&#8217;s guide to Super Bowl 50</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Super Bowl is the crowning night of America’s favorite pastime. Each year, football fans tune in to see who will take home the coveted Vince Lombardi Trophy, and the rest of America hangs around for the legendary commercials. Whether you’re a die-hard fan or dread Sunday nights in winter, we’re sharing 5 marketing ideas to help you score some sales this Super Bowl 50.<br />
<span id="more-21183"></span> </p>
<h2 style="color:#2b5201">Remind me again why I should care about the Super Bowl?</h2>
<p>The Super Bowl is the <a href="http://www.nfl.com/" target="_blank">National Football League</a>’s annual championship game. Aside from being football’s largest televised event each year, with over 100 million viewers, it’s also famous for the high price tag on its 30-second ads. This year, that price is said to be about <a href="http://fortune.com/2015/08/06/super-bowl-ad-cost/" target="_blank">$5 million per 30 seconds</a> (whoever said time is money, is right!). The high price pushes companies to pull out all the stops so their ad makes an impact. Each year the NFL also invites artists to perform during their 30-minute half-time show. Performers like Coldplay, Bruno Mars, and Beyonce are expected to make an appearance this year. </p>
<h2 style="color:#2b5201">Colors</h2>
<p>This year, the <a href="http://www.panthers.com/" target="_blank">Carolina Panthers</a> will be facing off against the <a href="http://www.denverbroncos.com/" target="_blank">Denver Broncos</a>. Even if you didn’t manage to score an advertising spot this year, you can tailor your onsite marketing efforts to catch the attention of sports fans or people in their entourage. Just like at Christmas or Valentine’s, you can make a few graphic design tweaks to get your site in the spirit and capitalize on Super Bowl fever. Each team’s colors are listed below for some inspiration: </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/02/broncos-300x174.png" alt="broncos" width="300" height="174" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-21185" /></p>
<p><strong>Broncos: <span style="color:#de6226">Orange</span>, <span style="color:#13264b">Navy Blue</span>, <span style="color:#fff;background-color:#000">White</span></strong></p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/02/panthers-300x300.png" alt="panthers" width="300" height="300" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-21184" /></p>
<p><strong>Panthers: <span style="color:#009ada">Panther Blue</span>, <span style="color:#000016">Black</span>, <span style="color:#d1d2d4">Silver</span>, <span style="color:#fff;background-color:#000">White</span></strong></p>
<p>To see this in action, check out <a href="https://www.covergirl.com/collections/nfl-collection" target="_blank">CoverGirl, an NFL sponsor</a>. They do a great job of targeting their products to the non-traditional sports fan (in other words, yes, women like football, too). Merchants selling apparel and accessories can easily promote products for fans to wear to show their support at the stadium or house party. </p>
<p>If you’re a merchant selling food-related goodies, you’re also in luck. Although football is an all-American sport, tickets for this particular event start in the thousands, out of reach of many Americans. Most people (like me) will be enjoying the game from a Super Bowl Party. This means it’s time to feature your fruit tray and promote easy-to-serve finger foods that fans can either bring to or serve at these parties. </p>
<p>If these aren’t options for you, try just interacting with customers on your social media pages. Succeeding in social media is not always about making the conversation about your brand. It’s just as important to participate in the conversation. Root for your favorite team or ask your fans on social media to chime in. You could consider holding a friendly social-only competition with small discounts or exclusive product giveaways as the prize.</p>
<h2 style="color:#2b5201">The Lingo:</h2>
<p>A few words you’ll hear (and can use in your marketing campaigns): </p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Touchdown:</strong> Football’s term for a goal. Each touchdown is worth 6 points, and the opportunity to score 1 additional point or Extra Point (by kicking it between the posts) or 2 additional points 2 point conversion (by running or passing the ball in again.)</li>
<li><strong>Field Goal:</strong> The only other way to score a point. A kicker must kick the ball between the posts to to receive 3 points.</li>
<li><strong>Rings:</strong> Although the winning team receives a trophy, each player receives an additional Super Bowl Ring. Cam Newton: 0, Peyton Manning: 1.</li>
<li><strong>Kick Off:</strong> The game officially starts Sunday, February 7 at 6:30 PM. And since most of us won’t be in attendance, we’ll be watching it on CBS.</li>
<li><strong>Quarterback (QB):</strong> This year, Cam Newton and Peyton Manning are the leading men&#8211;they get to throw the ball.</li>
<li><strong>Interception:</strong> When the opposing team catches the ball instead of the intended receiver. Great for the team that caught the ball, bad for the team who (mis)threw the ball.</li>
<li><strong>Dab:</strong> The dance quarterback Cam Newton does after he completes a successful touchdown. Great to know, when you see <a href="https://media.giphy.com/media/ga3AL3ZPcywec/giphy.gif" target="_blank">GIFs of him dancing</a> on the field all over social media.</li>
</ol>
<p>So there you have it, your merchant guide to enjoying Super Bowl 50. Whether you choose to take advantage of these tips this year, or just enjoy the game, we’ll see you at Kickoff! </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/merchants-guide-super-bowl-50/">The merchant&#8217;s guide to Super Bowl 50</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/merchants-guide-super-bowl-50/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>3 Essential Tips For Launching A Profitable Rewards Program [Infographic]</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-essential-tips-for-launching-a-profitable-rewards-program-infographic/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-essential-tips-for-launching-a-profitable-rewards-program-infographic/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 15:48:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21198</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>When you launch a store, your focus should be on customer acquisition. But at some point, your traffic and sales will start to plateau. If you’re at that point already, it’s time to turn your attention to customer retention. Today’s guest blogger, Darren DeMatas, co-founder of Selfstartr, an ecommerce consulting company helping merchants launch their [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-essential-tips-for-launching-a-profitable-rewards-program-infographic/">3 Essential Tips For Launching A Profitable Rewards Program [Infographic]</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>When you launch a store, your focus should be on <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-simple-growth-hacks-for-ecommerce-customer-acquisition/">customer acquisition</a>. But at some point, your traffic and sales will start to plateau. If you’re at that point already, it’s time to turn your attention to <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-building-blocks-improving-lead-retention/">customer retention</a>. Today’s guest blogger, Darren DeMatas, co-founder of <a href="https://selfstartr.com/" target="_blank">Selfstartr</a>, an ecommerce consulting company helping merchants launch their ideas and achieve their goals, tells you how.</em><br />
<span id="more-21198"></span><br />
A go-to retention strategy for many ecommerce businesses is to launch a rewards program. Why not? The average U.S. consumer is enrolled in over 13 loyalty programs! Tapping into your existing customer base makes a lot of sense:</p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>It is 6X more expensive to acquire a new customer than it is to keep one</li>
<li>The probability of converting an existing customer is 10X higher than a new prospect</li>
<li>Current customers spend 67% more than new ones</li>
</ul>
<p>The <a href="http://selfstartr.com/customer-loyalty-programs/" target="_blank">customer loyalty infographic from Selfstartr</a> shows that these programs can generate ROI if you take the right approach.  Here are three essential tips to launch a profitable rewards program that builds true loyalty.</p>
<h2 style="color:#de166c">1. Reward For Engagement</h2>
<p>Almost all loyalty programs reward customers for spending money (97%). But only 25% reward customers for engagement. It’s no wonder that 77% of them fail within two years.</p>
<p>Customers want to build a relationship that goes beyond money.  Prestashop loyalty add-ons like <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/referral-loyalty-programs/4414-all-in-one-rewards-loyalty-sponsorship-affiliation-fb.html" target="_blank">All-in-one Rewards</a> make this possible. In addition to purchases, you can reward customers for referring their friends to your site through blogs and social media.  This add-on allows you to easily give points for likes. Showing up on your customers’ Facebook wall helps expand your presence and create engagement.</p>
<p>Under Armour is a fantastic example of engagement-based rewards. They give customers points in exchange for exercising and healthy eating.</p>
<h2 style="color:#de166c">2. Don’t Make The Focus On Discounts</h2>
<p>71% of loyalty program members earn more than $100K/year. Not too shabby. While we all like a good deal, it’s safe to say that a saving an extra few bucks won’t really drive customers to purchase. According to Harvard Business professor Gerald Zaltman, <a href="http://hbswk.hbs.edu/item/the-subconscious-mind-of-the-consumer-and-how-to-reach-it" target="_blank">95% of our purchase decision</a> process occurs in the subconscious mind.</p>
<p>So price isn’t necessarily the first barrier you should try to overcome. Often, customers are not sure what product to buy. Clear contact information, links to customer service policies and live chat can help boost buyer confidence.</p>
<p>Show your customers you’re there for them, not just to collect money.</p>
<h2 style="color:#de166c">3. Show Customers That You’re Loyal To Them</h2>
<p>Show customers that you care about them more than their money. Make <a href="https://selfstartr.com/.%C2%A0https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/the-best-ways-to-build-customer-loyalty-for-your-online-store/" target="_blank">customer service friendly and accessible</a>, even for non-paying customers. You can save your product rewards for high dollar clients, but everyone deserves top notch service.</p>
<p>73% of consumers feel that loyalty programs are for businesses to show their loyalty to customers. The customer is always right, right? Treat them like you want them to come back and they actually might.</p>
<div style="clear:both">
	<a href="https://selfstartr.com/true-value-of-customer-loyalty-programs/" target="_blank"><br />
		<img src="https://2y3k762v0f153f3cbu4efo8g-wpengine.netdna-ssl.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/12/Value-Of-Customer-Loyalty.png" title="The True Value Of Customer Loyalty Programs" alt="The True Value Of Customer Loyalty Programs" border="0" /><br />
	</a>
</div>
<p>Courtesy of: <a href="https://selfstartr.com" target="_blank">Selfstartr</a></p>
<p>If you’re looking to improve your customer lifetime value, be sure to check out all the <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/503-referral-loyalty-programs" target="_blank">reward program add-ons</a> from Prestashop.</p>
<p>Darren has an MBA in Internet Marketing, but hangs his hat on a decade of experience in the trenches. Check out <a href="https://selfstartr.com/" target="_blank">Selfstartr</a> to learn more about ecommerce. Follow him on <a href="https://twitter.com/DarrenDeMatas" target="_blank">Twitter</a> and <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/internetmarketingmba" target="_blank">LinkedIn</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-essential-tips-for-launching-a-profitable-rewards-program-infographic/">3 Essential Tips For Launching A Profitable Rewards Program [Infographic]</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-essential-tips-for-launching-a-profitable-rewards-program-infographic/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Get ready for spring with our partner Amazon Payments</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-ready-spring-partner-amazon-payments/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-ready-spring-partner-amazon-payments/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 13:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop Partners]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21178</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>In the wake of Snowzilla, we’re all looking forward to leaving the cold, grey season behind us. In the spirit of warmer weather to come, our partner Amazon Payments has launched its “Bring On Spring” campaign this week. Merchants who register a new account by February 15th and make the Amazon Payments module commercially available [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-ready-spring-partner-amazon-payments/">Get ready for spring with our partner Amazon Payments</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In the wake of Snowzilla, we’re all looking forward to leaving the cold, grey  season behind us. In the spirit of warmer weather to come, our partner Amazon Payments has launched its “Bring On Spring” campaign this week. Merchants who register a new account by February 15th and make the Amazon Payments module commercially available in their online shop until March20th will pay no service fees during spring 2016. <a href="https://go.amazonservices.com/BoS_UK.html?ld=%20SPUKAP_BOS_B_PS" target="_blank">Click here to learn more</a>.<br />
<span id="more-21178"></span></p>
<h4 style="color:#f6b415">Amazon Payments &#8211; what do they do?</h4>
<p>For those unfamiliar with Amazon Payments, here is a brief overview: the company offers an online payment system that allows millions of Amazon customers to log in and pay on your site with the account information stored in their Amazon accounts. Customers no longer need to remember usernames and passwords, and there is no need to key in credit card and address information again either. Widgets ensure that buyers do not leave the merchant site during the purchasing process, therby ensuring a consistent brand experience.</p>
<h4 style="color:#f6b415">Easy to integrate</h4>
<p>You can activate Login and Pay with Amazon conveniently in your PrestaShop Back Office. To download the plugin file – if necessary – and get further information about the module, please visit the <a href="https://payments.amazon.co.uk/sp/prestashop?ld=%20SPUKAP_BOS_B_PS" target="_blank">Amazon Payments website</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-ready-spring-partner-amazon-payments/">Get ready for spring with our partner Amazon Payments</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/get-ready-spring-partner-amazon-payments/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>2016 Web Design Trends for your Online Store</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2016-web-design-trends-online-store/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2016-web-design-trends-online-store/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 13:30:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21163</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Trends come and go, and in the ecommerce industry, where updating web page design is as simple as swapping out a few lines of code, they can shift in an instant. To help guide your web design changes this year, we’ve asked members of our Agency Program to share their predictions for 2016 so you [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2016-web-design-trends-online-store/">2016 Web Design Trends for your Online Store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Trends come and go, and in the ecommerce industry, where updating web page design is as simple as swapping out a few lines of code, they can shift in an instant. To help guide your web design changes this year, we’ve asked members of our <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/certification-details">Agency Program</a> to share their predictions for 2016 so you can stay ahead of the pack.<br />
<span id="more-21163"></span> </p>
<h2 style="color:#1b9743">Trends from 2015</h2>
<p>First, let’s look at some 2015 trends that are sticking around. If your redesigned your website last year using any of these elements, you don’t have to change them. Armando Salvador, <strong>Chief Technical Officer</strong> at <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/es/asociados-agencia-web/plata/ecomm360">eComm360</a> predicts these trends are here to stay: </p>
<p><strong>Flat Design</strong><br />
Flat web design removes all traces of shadows, depth effects, bevels, gradients and three-dimensional effects to give a simple, minimalist look. This trends makes a website very clean and clear, and a seamless match for responsive design. Although this trend has been around for a few years already, we will continue to see it used in 2016.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/flat-desingquerolets-1024x506.png" alt="flat desing(querolets)" width="700" height="345" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21164" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.querolets.net/es/" target="_blank">Querolets</a></p>
<p><strong>Scroll to tell stories</strong><br />
In 2015, we saw a rise of web pages that seem to scroll to infinity. The scrolling web design not only gives great results, it’s perfect for developing story-like content because it limits the number of clicks a visitor has to make. Coupled with the increased use of mobile devices, this scrolling trend will remain the design preference of users in 2016.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/scrolllesraffineurs.png" alt="scroll(lesraffineurs)" width="404" height="854" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21170" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.lesraffineurs.com/" target="_blank">lesraffineurs</a></p>
<p><strong>Animations</strong><br />
Well-placed animations can greatly enrich the experience within any web website<br />
Here are some of the most popular: </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Loaders: entertains and lets visitors know exactly what’s going on.</li>
<li>Hover: lends itself to a more intuitive user experience, providing user feedback without having to click.</li>
<li>Slideshows: present images and videos without cluttering web design.</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/hovercanada.png" alt="hover(canada)" width="845" height="660" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-21167" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.canadahouse.es/en/" target="_blank">Canada House</a></p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/hoverclick-and-wine-1024x479.png" alt="hover(click and wine)" width="700" height="327" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21168" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.clickandwine.es/gb/" target="_blank">Click and Wine</a></p>
<p>Not all 2015 trends will be along for the ride in 2016. Mona from <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners/bronze/nurelm">NuRelm</a> says goodbye to: </p>
<p><strong>Flashy but Slow Sites</strong><br />
In 2015, there were many flashy sites that used hefty and sizable parallax styles or large file designs that look cool, but slow down users’ browsers to unbearable speeds. Designs should be clean, unique engaging, and easily accessible, but also easy to process both on the server-side. They should be easy on viewers’ eyes and easy to understand.</p>
<h2 style="color:#1b9743">Design Trends New to 2016</h2>
<p>Each new year brings new ideas. Here are the trends Armando from <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/es/asociados-agencia-web/plata/ecomm360">eComm360</a> is most looking forward to in 2016. </p>
<p><strong>Typography</strong><br />
Larger fonts, used expressively, will be more common.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/Tipografiacanadahouse-1024x506.png" alt="Tipografia(canadahouse)" width="700" height="345" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21171" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.canadahouse.es/en/" target="_blank">Canada House</a></p>
<p><strong>Fullscreen</strong><br />
Take advantage of the full width of devices: sliders with multiple images have been replaced with one, high-resolution image. With more advanced technology and improved hardware, larger designs can be better appreciated. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/fullscreentiny-cottons-1024x506.png" alt="fullscreen(tiny cottons)" width="700" height="345" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21165" /></p>
<p><a href="http://tinycottons.com/" target="_blank">Tiny Cottons</a></p>
<p><strong>Burger menu</strong><br />
The Burger menu, so prevalent in responsive designs, is now a regular feature on the websites, even those designed for larger devices. It has long been used for mobile, but as the minimalist trend continues, we see the burger menu replacing traditional dropdowns on desktop. </p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/menu-hamburguesaclick-and-wine-1024x496.png" alt="menu hamburguesa(click and wine)" width="700" height="339" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21169" /></p>
<p><a href="http://www.clickandwine.es/gb/" target="_blank">Click and Wine</a></p>
<p><strong>Ghost buttons</strong><br />
Ghost buttons have been increasingly integrated into today’s design. Virtually invisible, they take minimalism to the extreme. Activated via hover animations, they attract more attention from the user and encourage secondary actions.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/boton-fantasmaimage-republic-1024x487.png" alt="boton fantasma(image republic)" width="700" height="332" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21172" /></p>
<p><a href="http://image-republic.com/en/" target="_blank">Image Republic</a></p>
<p><strong>Grid options</strong><br />
Pinterest made this trend popular, and we’ll be seeing it adapted into web design this year. The design works very well when websites need to mix different types of information and invites unlimited and easy content navigation.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/01/gridtiny-cottons-1024x514.png" alt="grid(tiny cottons)" width="700" height="351" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-21166" /></p>
<p><a href="http://tinycottons.com/" target="_blank">Tiny Cottons</a></p>
<p>In 2016, Sam from <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners/bronze/nurelm">NuRelm</a> is looking forward to: </p>
<p><strong>Accessibility</strong><br />
We are expecting to see a rise in developers and designers implementing designs that  increase usability for those who have trouble accessing a computer or the internet. Whether it be physical touch limitation or sight impairment, new design trends are shifting to adapt to individual needs. We believe everyone should have the right to easily access the internet and browse the same as everyone else, and no company should ignore people that might have trouble browsing their own site.</p>
<h2 style="color:#1b9743">In a nutshell</h2>
<p>Whether you’re an online merchant looking to redesign your website or a designer picking up ideas for new PrestaShop themes, here are a few tips to keep in mind. </p>
<ol>
<li>Design trends should be carefully considered before integrating them into your online shop. The “flashy-er” a trend, the quicker it can potentially die out. If you’re not looking to redesign your shop for a few years, pick the trends you want to integrate wisely.</li>
<li>Don’t forget about your audience, the customer. Regardless of how “cool” your website is, it should ultimately help to convert your customer. Make sure your new design doesn’t detract from the products you’re trying to sell.</li>
<li><a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/6-ab-tests-for-optimizing-your-online-store/">A/B test</a> your ideas, if you can. Just because something is trendy, doesn’t mean it will work for your online shop. Make sure that adding these new designs don’t put a damper on your current sales.</li>
</ol>
<p>Looking for some great agencies to give your <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/">online store</a> a rocking website design? Pick from our list of <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/en/web-agency-partners">Official Agencies</a>. Think we missed an important trend for 2016? Share in the comments below!</p>
<div class="row">
<div class="col-sm-6"><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/02/ecomm360-1024x270.png" alt="ecomm360" width="700" height="184" class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-13059" /></div>
<div class="col-sm-6"><img src="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/files/2016/02/nurelm.png" alt="nurelm" width="220" height="127" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-13054" /></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2016-web-design-trends-online-store/">2016 Web Design Trends for your Online Store</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2016-web-design-trends-online-store/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Reader Poll: We want to hear from you!</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/reader-poll-want-hear/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/reader-poll-want-hear/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 13:30:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[PrestaShop News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21129</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Hi PrestaShop Community, Help us to create the perfect blog for you. The questions will take you 2 minutes. The answers will give you great ecommerce content for the rest of the year. Take the survey! Thank you and Happy Selling!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/reader-poll-want-hear/">Reader Poll: We want to hear from you!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi PrestaShop Community, </p>
<p>Help us to create the perfect blog for you. The questions will take you 2 minutes. The answers will give you great ecommerce content for the rest of the year.</p>
<div class="text-center" style="margin-bottom: 20px"><a href="https://jliu08ps.typeform.com/to/iE9Vzy" target="_blank" style="font-size:23px">Take the survey!</a></div>
<p>Thank you and Happy Selling!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/reader-poll-want-hear/">Reader Poll: We want to hear from you!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/reader-poll-want-hear/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 steps to a successful Valentine&#8217;s Day Sale</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-steps-successful-valentines-day-sale/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-steps-successful-valentines-day-sale/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 13:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21140</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Valentine’s day is just around the corner. Lovers and relationship hopefuls will spend an estimated $18.9 billion (according to NRF) on gifts, dinners and more on the big day. With customers in love and ready to spend, here are 5 steps you can count to help you reach successful Valentine’s day sales. 1. Think Mobile [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-steps-successful-valentines-day-sale/">5 steps to a successful Valentine&#8217;s Day Sale</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Valentine’s day is just around the corner. Lovers and relationship hopefuls will spend an estimated <a href="https://nrf.com/media/press-releases/cupid-shower-americans-jewelry-candy-this-valentines-day" target="_blank">$18.9 billion (according to NRF)</a> on gifts, dinners and more on the big day. With customers in love and ready to spend, here are 5 steps you can count to help you reach successful Valentine’s day sales.<br />
<span id="more-21140"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#e34894">1. Think Mobile</h2>
<p>Mobile is fast becoming the preferred shopping channel in leading ecommerce markets like the UK and Germany. With <a href="http://resources.mobify.com/50-mobile-commerce-stats.html" target="_blank">30% of customers saying they’ll abandon a mobile</a> purchase if the site isn’t optimized, you would do well to make this a priority during peak sales periods like Valentine’s Day. Make sure your emails are adapted to mobile viewing, and that the transition from email to site to checkout is seamless. If your website isn’t mobile-responsive already, make that first on your list of things to do to get ready for the sales season.</p>
<h2 style="color:#e34894">2. Create an attractive offer</h2>
<p>As with other sale periods, the challenge at Valentine’s Day is to come up with an offer that stands out from the crowd. Merchants who sell traditional Valentine’s Day goods like flowers, chocolates, stuffed animals and lingerie will be under exceptional pressure to catch the consumer eye. Discounts are an obvious option, but playing on price alone can be hit or miss. Consider offering <a href="https://www.ice-watch.com/uk-en/ice-sili/ice-love-p-26729.htm?coul_att_detailID=1266&amp;utm_source=B2C+-+Customers+-+Contacts+-+Ice-Watch&amp;utm_campaign=97b098e6ae-2016_01_14_love_teaser_ALL_ALL&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_term=0_b847164ea2-97b098e6ae-273191485&amp;mc_cid=97b098e6ae&amp;mc_eid=754b62a6a1" target="_blank">limited edition items</a> or custom product bundles that play on a sense of urgency and the current holiday theme. </p>
<p>Another option is to combine attractive sales with personalized marketing efforts. Valentine’s Day is stressful for some people, so offering an added value in the form of gift guides, curation, or even a vamped up live chat can be the detail that convinces customers to shop with you. Think about what problem or desire your products respond to, and then focus on getting that message to your customers via your blog, newsletter and email campaigns. </p>
<h2 style="color:#e34894">3. Promote</h2>
<p>After you’ve come up with the perfect offer, make sure customers are aware of your sale. Here are a few suggestions:</p>
<p>- <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/using-pop-ups-for-your-online-store-best-practices-and-examples-for-2015/"><strong>Pop Ups or Pop Ins</strong></a><br />
Pop-ups and pop-ins promote your sale to people who are already on your website. Because they take up your entire web page, they’re sure to capture shoppers’ attention&#8211; but they can also be seen as disruptive. Be sure to place limitations on the number of times a shopper will receive the prompt so they don’t leave with a bad impression.</p>
<p>- <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/4-awesome-ideas-valentines-day-gift-guides/"><strong>Gift Guides</strong></a><br />
Gift guides are a versatile way to promote your products. They’re especially helpful for shoppers who are stymied for gift ideas, or who waited until the last minute. A well put-together gift guide directs shoppers with different needs to the perfect present. If you have a blog, use it to showcase your products to your readers. Consider putting together an advice-based post that gives customers added value in addition to presenting your product.</p>
<p>- <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-key-steps-successful-email-campaign/"><strong>Email Marketing</strong></a><br />
Email remains one of the most effective ways of getting your message out: you reach directly into your customer’s inbox for a chance to grab their attention and drive traffic to your website. Be sure you have a catchy subject line to reel them in, and that the transition from inbox to landing page goes off without a hitch. Depending on your promotion, you might also consider a multi-tiered email campaign that divides the focus between price-based offers and <a href="http://www.splio4.com/mr/6fU0is7q4/3390/1877180697.html" target="_blank">unique value adds</a> that are likely to differentiate you from the competition. Think about how you can delight your customer this year, in addition to saving her money.</p>
<p>- <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/3-steps-launching-sem-campaign-google-adwords/"><strong>Google Ads</strong></a><br />
This is potentially the most costly promotion tool in your marketing kit. Whether you manage your campaign directly with Google Adwords, or use a third-party service provider, you’ll have to pay to use this option. Around holiday sales, bids for keywords like “Valentine’s Day” and “Gifts” tend to be higher. However, the visibility you will gain has great earning potential for your website. You should evaluate your resources and allocate budget accordingly; Google Ads can be a great boost, but if you don’t have a compelling offer or give customers a reason to trust you, then no amount of traffic will help you reach your sales goals.</p>
<p>- <strong>Website banner displays</strong><br />
Just like popups and popins, website banners only promote your sale to people already shopping on your site. The advantage is that a banner is not as intrusive, and unlike popups and popins, customers can’t simply close and forget about them. (Here&#8217;s how to change them with the <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/prestashop-modules-customizing-look-homepage/">default template</a>). They’re a great place to use theme-specific images and highlight perks like free shipping and gift wrapping. Think about adding in a shipping cut off reminder as well. Everything you do to simplify the shopping experience gets you a step closer to a conversion.</p>
<p>- <strong>Social Media</strong><br />
Promoting your sale on social media is a great way to reach shoppers who are interested but haven’t made a purchase with you. It’s also a great opportunity for your ad to be shared among shoppers’ online friends. You might consider a social-only promotion or contest to drum up interest.</p>
<p>Do you know you plan on <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-valentines-day-e-commerce-marketing-ideas/">promoting your valentine&#8217;s day sales</a>? For more help and advice, check out our <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/10-valentines-day-e-commerce-marketing-ideas/">Valentine&#8217;s Day Marketing</a> article! </p>
<h2 style="color:#e34894">4. Test</h2>
<p>With a limited time to convert customers, it’s important to test your website and the offers that you’ve developed. Make sure the coupons and promotions you’re promoting actually work: it sounds obvious, but when you’re rushing to get things just right and in time, there’s always a possibility of a technical error slipping in. Don’t wait to find out on the day of the sale.</p>
<p>Besides testing your promotions, here are a few other tasks you should complete before you launch your sale: </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>Test links from all your advertising</li>
<li>Try placing an order (this is especially critical when you allow customers to customize products)</li>
<li>Complete the order with each of your payment options. There is nothing worse than having a customer discard a purchase because they were unable to pay.</li>
</ul>
<p>Valentine’s Day is a big one for last-minute orders, so it’s more important than ever to ensure quick and easy ordering. </p>
<h2 style="color:#e34894">5. Analyze</h2>
<p>Last, but certainly not least: schedule time for post-holiday sales analysis. Use this time to review your sales predictions and to see if the sales met or fell short of your target goals. Ask yourself questions like: </p>
<ul style="padding-left: 30px">
<li>What worked well this year?</li>
<li>What can be improved?</li>
<li>Which trends would we like to test for the next holiday sale?</li>
<li>Which trends were surprising and warrant another look?</li>
<li>Which ideas, if any, should we stop testing?</li>
</ul>
<p>The conclusions you draw from your analysis will be important for making predictions for your next sales holiday. It&#8217;s also important to analyze the products you have leftover and brainstorm another promotion to clear this year&#8217;s Valentine&#8217;s Day products. </p>
<hr width="20%" align="left" />
<p>Are you ready for Valentine&#8217;s day 2016? Share any tips you’ve learned in the comments or come back and tell us how these steps helped you achieve your sales goal this year! </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-steps-successful-valentines-day-sale/">5 steps to a successful Valentine&#8217;s Day Sale</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/5-steps-successful-valentines-day-sale/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Success Story: How crazy is it to sell perishable goods online? Not Half Nuts!</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/success-story-how-crazy-is-it-to-sell-perishable-goods-online-not-half-nuts/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/success-story-how-crazy-is-it-to-sell-perishable-goods-online-not-half-nuts/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 13:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Success Stories]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21123</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The seamless process of online shopping&#8211;click a button and receive your goods&#8211;means many of us take for granted the complicated logistics that allow our online purchases to make it to our doorstep without delay. In today’s success story, Mary Ziegler, co-owner of HalfNuts.net, let’s us in on how her company makes sure every package arrives [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/success-story-how-crazy-is-it-to-sell-perishable-goods-online-not-half-nuts/">Success Story: How crazy is it to sell perishable goods online? Not Half Nuts!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The seamless process of online shopping&#8211;click a button and receive your goods&#8211;means many of us take for granted the complicated logistics that allow our online purchases to make it to our doorstep without delay. In today’s success story, Mary Ziegler, co-owner of <a href="https://www.halfnuts.net/" target="_blank">HalfNuts.net</a>, let’s us in on how her company makes sure every package arrives with a hitch.<br />
<span id="more-21123"></span><br />
<strong>JL: Tell us about Half Nuts and the products you sell.</strong></p>
<p><strong>MZ:</strong> As our name suggests, we sell a wide variety of nuts that are raw, roasted, salted, and even topped with delectable coatings, such as chocolate or butter toffee. The other half of Half Nuts is a wide assortment of candies, chocolates, dried fruit, snack mixes and most notably, our proprietary Ziegler Giant Bar.  </p>
<p><strong>JL: What is the Ziegler Giant Bar? </strong></p>
<p><strong>MZ:</strong> The Ziegler Giant Bar was candy bar created by The Ziegler Candy Company. The name is no coincidence&#8230; the Ziegler Candy Company was run by my husband’s family for four generations before they closed in the 1970s. Growing up around the candy factory inspired my husband to make candy a part of his career path at Half Nuts. Today, we continue to offer the original Giant Bar in the same molds, with the same recipe, as an homage to the Ziegler Candy family history. </p>
<p><strong>JL: How did your online store come to be? </strong></p>
<p><strong>MZ:</strong> We started in our brick and mortar business in 1990. As a convenience to our local customers, we set up a website and listed all of our products online, so they could see what we had and shop without actually coming to the store. Since our first website debuted in 2002, we’ve redesigned and re-launched it several times before settling on the current one. We have expanded from just our online catalog for our local community, to becoming a full scale national retailer of nuts, candy, and lots of other treats.</p>
<p>When we hired our web developer, Arafat, we were impressed with his website portfolio and the overall design of the shop. That’s why we’ve stayed with him since PrestaShop 1.5.6 and have recently upgraded to PrestaShop 1.6. Arafat takes much pride in his work, and has custom built us a great PrestaShop website.</p>
<p><strong>JL: What challenges have you encountered selling perishable goods?</strong></p>
<p><strong>MZ:</strong> The main challenge we have shipping the products is the fact that they are perishable and we want them to arrive as fresh as possible. The perks of living in Milwaukee include having nice cool shipping weather for most of the year. However, as our sales grew online and we started shipping much more to the South, but also to the East and the West coasts, we had to deal with the hot weather those regions are apt to have.  Some have shipping weather all year round that is poses a problem for us. Our vendors often use ice bricks to ship product to us, and we then offer those ice bricks to our customers for free.  </p>
<p>Although this helped keep the products cool, the weight of the ice bricks increased the shipping costs for our customer. Because of this, we implemented the Connect to <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/518-shipping-logistics" target="_blank">UPS</a> and the <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/shipping-costs/20047-usps-rate-calculator-pro.html" target="_blank">USPS Shipping</a> modules, to let our customers pick the shipping option they prefer. We let them choose whether they want a service that tells them the exact date they’ll receive their package, like UPS does, or if they prefer the less expensive option, with the United States Postal Service.</p>
<p>Another thing that we offer are Styrofoam coolers. These provide great insulation for the “meltables” we ship, without excessively weighing them down.  While it cuts down on weight, it still increases costs due to the size of the package.  This is why we use two shipping modules that offer two different shipping options.  Letting our customers choose their own shipping method has helped keep our costs down and in turn, keeps our customers happy. </p>
<p><strong>JL: With holidays like Valentine’s around the corner, how do you prepare? </strong></p>
<p><strong>MZ:</strong> Valentine’s, Easter, Halloween, and Christmas&#8230;all the major holidays&#8230;are busy times for us. We start promoting for these events about 15 days ahead of time for the smaller holidays, and a month prior to the major ones like Christmas and Easter. We’ll add features like <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/pop-in-pop-up/19431-pop-promo.html" target="_blank">a pop-up notification</a> and we offer holiday discounts for online orders. For current customers, we’ll remind them about our store with an <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/500-newsletter-sms" target="_blank">email marketing</a> campaign and offer the same holiday discount. To prepare logistically, for holidays and other busy times, we always arrange extra staff to fulfill orders on a timely basis, usually within 24 hours.</p>
<hr width="20%" align="left">
<p>Do you think you have what it takes to start selling perishable goods online? Get started today with our <a href="http://www.prestashop.com/">eCommerce software</a>. Want more inspiration? Check out other PrestaShop merchants in these previous <a href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/category/ecommerce-success-stories/">success stories</a>!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/success-story-how-crazy-is-it-to-sell-perishable-goods-online-not-half-nuts/">Success Story: How crazy is it to sell perishable goods online? Not Half Nuts!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/success-story-how-crazy-is-it-to-sell-perishable-goods-online-not-half-nuts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Should your online store offer gift cards?</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/online-store-offer-gift-cards/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/online-store-offer-gift-cards/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2016 13:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Julie Liu]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21121</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that in 2014 gift card spending grew to $100 billion? Since their inception, gift cards have steadily grown in popularity. Today we’ll go over the basics of gift cards to help you determine if they’re a good fit for your online shop. What are gift cards? There are 2 major kinds of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/online-store-offer-gift-cards/">Should your online store offer gift cards?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did you know that in <a href="http://www.pymnts.com/news/2015/inside-the-motives-of-a-gift-card-buyer-why-the-industry-continues-to-boom/" target="_blank">2014 gift card spending grew to $100 billion</a>? Since their inception, gift cards have steadily grown in popularity. Today we’ll go over the basics of gift cards to help you determine if they’re a good fit for your online shop.<br />
<span id="more-21121"></span></p>
<h2 style="color:#251b5a">What are gift cards?</h2>
<p>There are 2 major kinds of gift cards: open-loop (bank) gift cards, which are supported by major payment solutions like Visa, MasterCard and American Express, and closed-loop  (or retail) cards,  which are only accepted at specific retailers. In this article, we’ll just be addressing closed-loop gift cards your own shop can issue. </p>
<h2 style="color:#251b5a">Gift card pros for online stores</h2>
<p>Gift cards are great not only for customers, but also for the merchants who sell them. Here are a few great reasons to offer gift cards on your online shop: </p>
<ol>
<li>It’s easy for the customer&#8211;they don’t need to know the recipient’s address or preferences.</li>
<li>End customers get to pick products they actually want, which reduces the number of returns on your site.</li>
<li>Your cash flow gets a boost: you’ll be paid before you even ship the product.</li>
<li>They’re convenient, but more personal than money.</li>
<li>Gift cards give new customers that may have been hesitant to purchase from you otherwise a reason to get to know you.</li>
<li>Customers generally pay full price and <a href="https://www.cebglobal.com/exbd/financial-services/tower-group/gift-cards/index.page?" target="_blank">spend more than the value of the gift card</a>.</li>
</ol>
<h2 style="color:#251b5a">Gift card cons for online stores</h2>
<p>Of course, with the good comes the bad. Here are some of the negatives of making gift cards available on your shop:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Increased bookkeeping.</strong> You’ll need to keep track of the initial gift card purchase, as well as the product order, which is when the gift card is actually redeemed.</li>
<li><strong>No returns, only exchanges.</strong> For most credit card processors, funds can only be returned to the original purchaser’s card. This makes issuing returns to the gift recipient impossible.</li>
<li><strong>Potential for fraud.</strong> In some instances, a scammer could purchase the gift card, then drain the value of the gift card <em>before you</em>, the merchant, realize that the original order is fraudulent.</li>
</ol>
<h2 style="color:#251b5a">How to set up gift cards in PrestaShop</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Install a <a href="http://addons.prestashop.com/en/pricing-promotion-prestashop-modules/17452-gift-card.html" target="_blank">gift card module</a>.</strong> Although it’s possible to manually create each gift card as customers purchase them with our built-in voucher capabilities, we’ve created a module that helps you manage your gift cards. Once you’ve installed a gift card module, you’re ready to set it up. </li>
<li><strong>Decide on gift card amounts / denominations.</strong> You’ll want to offer gift cards in denominations that make sense for your product selection. If your average order value is , make sure you offer gift card amounts that reflect that. Offering  gift cards won’t really make sense in this example. </li>
<li><strong>Set the expiration date.</strong> Be aware of laws that regulate this in your country. For example, if you’re based <a href="http://www.ncsl.org/research/financial-services-and-commerce/gift-cards-and-certificates-statutes-and-legis.aspx" target="_blank">in the US, gift cards cannot expire within 5 years</a> of the purchase. This is just the baseline. Additional state laws may further limit the expiration date. </li>
<li><strong>Provide all product FAQ’s in the product description.</strong> For example, let customers know where the gift card is valid. If you have a physical location, can it be used there? Can the gift card be used on clearance items? If you will assess any additional fees, list them here as well. This ensures that you not only address your customer’s concerns, but you also ensure that there is no confusion about how gift cards are to be used on your website. </li>
<li><strong>List and promote your gift card.</strong> It’s not enough to just create your gift card. Be sure to add a link in your footer and try searching “gift card” in your search bar to verify that it’s easy to find. Next, try promoting the gift card on a homepage slider or in your gift product category. </li>
</ol>
<p>It’s your turn. Tell us why you do or don’t offer gift cards to your online shop. Have any good or bad experiences share them in the comments below. Not running an online shop yet? Get started today with PrestaShop. </p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/online-store-offer-gift-cards/">Should your online store offer gift cards?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/online-store-offer-gift-cards/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>2 Quick Ways Retailers Can Improve Inventory in 2016</title>
		<link>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2-quick-ways-retailers-can-improve-inventory-2016/</link>
		<comments>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2-quick-ways-retailers-can-improve-inventory-2016/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 13:30:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Preston's Friends]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Ecommerce Tips and Advice]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/?p=21134</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>The holidays are over. Let’s all take a deep breath. It was the best holiday season on record for online retailers, as online sales jumped a whopping 20% over 2014; but don’t pop your leftover champagne just yet. There are a few areas of improvement that became clear during the holidays, and inventory is one [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2-quick-ways-retailers-can-improve-inventory-2016/">2 Quick Ways Retailers Can Improve Inventory in 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The holidays are over. Let’s all take a deep breath. </p>
<p>It was the best holiday season on record for online retailers, as online sales jumped a whopping <a href="http://www.mastercardadvisors.com/modules/news/a_happy_holiday_season_for_retailers.html" target="_blank">20%</a> over 2014; but don’t pop your leftover champagne just yet. There are a few areas of improvement that became clear during the holidays, and inventory is one of them. </p>
<p>Out of stock situations are embarrassing: you work hard to get shoppers to your store with clever advertising, entice them with your great prices and helpful product descriptions&#8211;but then they can’t add an item to their cart because you’re all out of it. Let’s make sure that never happens again.<br />
<span id="more-21134"></span><br />
Inventory is an inherently messy part of retail. Even the most successful retailers have ended up with too much or too little stock at some point, but that doesn’t have to be the case anymore, thanks to data. A quick look into historical sales data and best selling products for your specific vertical can determine which products <a href="http://www.wiser.com/wisepricer?utm_source=PrestaShop&amp;utm_medium=gp&amp;utm_campaign=1-16&amp;utm_content=2inventory" target="_blank">improve profit margins</a> and sell well consistently. Let’s dig deeper into these two ideas.</p>
<h2 style="color:#38315d">How Historical Sales Data Can Help</h2>
<p>When you change anything about your business, it’s important to have the data to figure out where you’ve come from and what impact your tweaks are making. If a product isn’t selling well, maybe it’s because the pricing was uncompetitive or maybe it’s just because unseasonably warm weather kept shoppers from buying it (this is a common issue for clothing retailers). Either way, knowing how many sold and under what conditions historically will tell you what strategy is most effective. </p>
<p>Like most parts of online retail, inventory is an ongoing process. You can’t just order once and sit back and relax. Instead, an <a href="http://www.wiser.com/assortment?utm_source=PrestaShop&amp;utm_medium=gp&amp;utm_campaign=1-16&amp;utm_content=2inventory" target="_blank">optimized inventory</a> must be constantly reevaluated to figure out which products and in what quantities worked, and what you should avoid in the future. In the case of inventory, it’s definitely true that you have to look back in order to move forward on the best foot. </p>
<h2 style="color:#38315d">Why You Should Track Best Sellers</h2>
<p>You already know that your product assortment has a huge impact on your success as a seller and some products are more important than others. The <a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/davelavinsky/2014/01/20/pareto-principle-how-to-use-it-to-dramatically-grow-your-business/" target="_blank">Pareto Principle</a> suggests that 80% of your sales will come from 20% of your stock, and that’s where best sellers come in. Having the top items in your vertical will draw shoppers to your site and your pricing will help them complete the purchase. So how do you make sure that you’re always stocked up on the hottest items that will take your online shop to the next level? </p>
<p>That’s where data comes back in. In order to find the best new products to add to your assortment, you need to keep track of how they’re selling and how they’re ranked on top marketplaces, especially Amazon. First, retailers need to choose the category or categories that will expand their selling capacity. This makes it possible to pinpoint the products that will increase sales. Next, a combination of <a href="http://blog.wiser.com/drive-the-bandwagon-how-to-catch-assortment-trends-early/?utm_source=PrestaShop&amp;utm_medium=gp&amp;utm_campaign=1-16&amp;utm_content=2inventory" target="_blank">popularity trends</a> (such as rating and rank on Amazon over time), cost, and pricing information will give you an idea of how volatile the item is and how much you’d be able to make from each sale. After all, you’ll only want to add the products that are consistently highly rated and the most profitable to make the most of your selling experience. </p>
<p>An advanced last step would be to perform a <a href="http://blog.wiser.com/how-to-enhance-assortment-discovery-using-market-price-intelligence/?utm_source=PrestaShop&amp;utm_medium=gp&amp;utm_campaign=1-16&amp;utm_content=2inventory" target="_blank">gap analysis</a> based on the top products you find. Sure, some best selling products might have slim margins, but maybe all of your competitors carry them. In that case, it might be a good idea to put your typical margins to the side and carry it anyway to avoid losing customers. You can always make up those margin dollars on unique products that you don’t have to price quite as competitively. </p>
<h2 style="color:#38315d">How to Speed up Inventory Improvement</h2>
<p>The easiest way to keep up with best sellers is by automating the process. That way you’ll never sleep on the top selling products again. Now that the holidays are over, all retailers are looking for the next top products that will speed up sales closer to where they were in mid December. The post holiday sales slump doesn’t have to be a reality with data-driven assortment planning. The combination of internal historical sales data and data from monitoring best sellers can help any retailer keep with trends and even lead the pack in their vertical.</p>
<h4 style="color:#38315d">About the Author</h4>
<p>Angelica Valentine is the Content Marketing Manager at <a href="http://www.wiser.com/?utm_source=PrestaShop&amp;utm_medium=gp&amp;utm_campaign=1-16&amp;utm_content=2inventory" target="_blank">Wiser</a>, the leading provider of data-driven pricing and merchandising solutions for retailers, brands, and manufacturers. Angelica is an Oakland native who loves writing, exploring, and participating in music, food, and cultural events around the Bay Area.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2-quick-ways-retailers-can-improve-inventory-2016/">2 Quick Ways Retailers Can Improve Inventory in 2016</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en">EN - Ecommerce blog by PrestaShop</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://www.prestashop.com/blog/en/2-quick-ways-retailers-can-improve-inventory-2016/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
